Welcome to the presentation what's new
item substitution with Copilot one of
the sessions of the Business Central
launch event.
My name is Predrag Maricic and today
with me Volodymyr Synchuk. Um together
we will try to explain how Copilot can
actually help with making item
substitutions in Business Central.
The agenda is quite short. We will try
to take a look on the existing
functionality and how Copilot is
changing the experience. After that
we're going to take a look under the
hood and see how we designed this
functionality.
Volodymyr will put the Copilot in action
and show you demo and after that we will
just provide some general instructions
and information about Copilot in
Business Central.
So it's no secret that Business Central
is investing heavily to get more AI
experience in the product and item
substitution is one of the features
from that family.
Existing item substitution functionality
is designed for users to be able to
define alternative item in case when the
primary item is out of stock or simply
needs to be replaced. So the idea is to
accelerate the whole inventory process
and
in order to do that user would need to
go to the item and then choose
substitution from the list of the
existing items. That would mean trying
to find similar items from the huge list
and just imagine having my bike store
with thousands of different items.
Some of them could be different just by
color or by producer. Essentially the
process could be very time-consuming and
error-prone.
So how about being able to go to a
Business Central, choose item and then
just say Business Central, can you find
some substitution candidates so that I
can choose from it? So that's exactly
what Copilot is
is trying to help with. So with the new
functionality, user will be able to
choose action to to suggest with Copilot
and then get automatically suggestion
for each of these items.
Let's now take a look on how we develop
this functionality.
So the first challenge for us was
actually to collect all the item related
information. As you can see on this
slide, the information was scattered
across different tables. So we had to go
to each of those tables and create
consolidate consolidated table which
contains information shown on this
slide.
This obviously was done to improve
performance and after that point, we are
getting all that information and sending
to Copilot to define keywords and
synonyms which then be used to
to to do filtering and find appropriate
items.
Not only that, so
after that we are committed to provide
results which should be reliable and
that's why we are using LLM to do
re-ranking of the results. Basically
define
which items are the most similar to the
original item.
Um
So how how how about confidence? It is
very important for us to build that
trust between the product and and user.
And there are a lot of rumors and
comments about AI generated results and
of course we want to present that to
users and make sure that user also
understand
level of confidence that Business
Central is providing with those results.
So
imagine situation where we have related
item which
is not quite the same as the original
one, but there are similarities.
Um We still want to be able to show that
to the user, but as you can see on this
screenshot, the second item is on the
list with the with lower confidence. We
want to let user know that this one is
probably not the perfect match, but it's
still something that user can choose.
There are also additional capabilities
to make this functionality flexible
enough for user that Vladimir will
demonstrate a bit later.
Now, let's take a look on how we can
activate item substitution feature.
So, similar like other Copilot
capabilities, there is page called
Copilot and AI capabilities, and in
order to activate item substitution
feature, it is needed to enable item
called create product information.
So, yes, this sentence looks like a bug,
but it's actually not. The initial idea
of for us was to deliver a bit more
functionalities around item
substitution, so not only the item
substitution.
However, due to
very strict and diligent process of
verifying feature against the
against the reliable AI standards,
we had to postpone one one piece of this
functionality for
for the future.
But now it's time to put Copilot in
action. So, Vladimir, can you please
show how this feature looks like right
now?
Yes, thank you, Pradeep.
Let's have a quick look how our item
substitution with Copilot works.
So, we start like from item list, we
pick let's pick guest chair.
And then as always, we go to item
substitutions.
And here we have our new magic button.
So, let's see what we are getting here.
What's happening behind the scene is we
are taking item description and we are
sending it to LLM to extract search
keywords like both main search terms and
additional search terms.
And then based on those search terms,
we do
search in actually all fields that
project mentioned before.
And then we get a list of items, a list
of candidates. So, after that we do
re-ranking using embedding to get like
the best results.
So, as you can see for our Gesture
black, we got some chairs, Gesture on
top. Uh
but we also got something which is
called conference table. And why is
that?
Uh let's try to see.
I'm going to open this conference table
item.
And I know that it should
have some extended text.
And here we have
a statement that we recommend our
Gesture
with this product. So, as product
mentioned before,
since we are doing search through all
these additional fields and tables, this
table also is getting to the candidates.
And then uh
apparently embedding decided that it's
good enough to be included into the
result.
Uh but let's see
let's check our confidence in that
result.
I'm going to switch the mode.
So, now we can see that Gesture
they are having high score and high
confidence and conference table has low
score.
In this example, what if instead of
guest chair, our main criteria is to
have a black chair?
In that case, we can just adjust some
prompt and do
any chair black
and then generate result.
So, we get our black chair on top with a
high score.
We also have
different modes of search. Balance,
which is by default, make sure that at
least one of the main search terms is
included in the result of search. And
then additional search terms are
optional.
Permissive
you can use if any search terms is
enough for item to be included into
candidates. And then precise mode if if
you want all the search terms to be
included. Let me just show you
how the precise mode works.
So, in that case, we got one result,
which is black chair, and that should be
enough. So, I'm going to insert this one
into item substitution.
And let me show you one more trick is
I want to create a new item
where I will not mention chair at all.
So, let's call it seat for one person
black.
And then let's try to get substitution
with Copilot for this one.
It is
Now, we got all our chairs even though
we did not mention chairs.
So, this is Yeah, we can insert them
all. I should also probably mention some
limitations that we have with this
product is that
first and probably the most important
that you need to have
quite good description of the item. So,
it has a meaning and
yeah,
uh
embedding vector can be built in a good
way for that one. Uh we also tested it
in English only. It should work on all
other languages, but just to mention
that we did testing only in English.
And there is also since we have um
consolidated table for the all fields
that we use in search, it is updated
periodically, but there might be some
delay
after you update the item or insert a
new one.
So, you have to wait a little bit before
you can use
substitution for this item that you
updated or created.
Thank you, Frederick.
Thank you so much Vladimir. Bunch of
exciting scenarios that Vladimir showed,
but some of the topics we actually
didn't manage to cover in this session.
So, that's why I would like also to draw
your attention on couple more topics
that you can find in other sessions.
So, part of my team also developed the
other
feature called sales line suggestion
with Copilot. This functionality was
released already in the previous wave,
but there are
there are couple of new exciting things
in this in that functionality.
Platform team also delivered data search
which we are using and that also could
be nice resource for you to learn how we
are improving data search across the
product. Then analyze assist with
Copilot and then for admins how to set
up Copilot in Business Central. And
finally for developers, there are good
resource on how to extend Copilot within
the Business Central using AL AL code.
Finally, I would like to address couple
of questions that we are usually
getting. All these Copilot features are
coming with no cost with existing
Business Central
license.
Also for partners um
it it is probably useful to know that
Copilot features are only available in
our cloud version of Business Central,
while on-premise on-prem versions are
unfortunately
without, um,
without Copilot functionalities.
Um, and then finally, there is always
question of, how does Copilot, um,
features in BC approach safety? So, you
already heard that, um,
we we spent quite a lot of time to get
the functionality aligned,
uh, with responsible AI standards. That
includes safety, security, privacy,
um, transparency, and accountability.
So, for more specifically for this
feature, for item substitution with
Copilot, we spent significantly more
time going through different reviews and
testing than for development itself. So,
Microsoft Business Central is fully
committed to to get aligned with those
standards.
I hope you enjoyed this session, and
thank you very much for watching it.